

Hugo Thimonier, PhD

Paris■ thimonier.hugo@gmail.com• +33.6.47.67.15.17• Websitein LinkedIn• GitHub

♂ Google Scholar 💢 arXiv

About Me

I am a Multimodal Research Scientist at Emobot, working on **Machine Learning (ML) for Audio and Video**. I hold a PhD in Computer Science from CentraleSupelec focused on **deep learning for tabular data**, in particular **anomaly detection** and **self-supervised learning** for tabular data. Prior to my PhD, I worked as a deep learning scientist intern at L'Oreal R&I where I focused on ML for video.

Education

Ph.D CentraleSupélec, LISN, Computer Science

2020 - 2024

- **Title**: Advancing Anomaly Detection in Tabular Data: A Case-Study on Credit Card Fraud Identication.
- Supervisors: Bich-Liên Doan, Fabrice Popineau, Arpad Rimmel.
- Jury: Louise Travé-Massuyès, Alain Celisse, Marius Kloft, Gaël Varoquaux and Alamir Mazen.

M.Eng	ENSAE , Statistics, Probabilities and Computer Science	2018 - 2020
M.Sc	ENS Paris-Saclay, Normalien Fonctionnaire-Stagiaire	2015 - 2020
DU	Paris 1 - Panthéon Sorbonne, Russian	2020 - 2022

Experience _____

Emobot ♀, AI Research Scientist

Paris, Fr 2024 - now

CentraleSupélec, LISN, PhD Candidate

Paris, Fr 2020 - 2024

- Topics: Anomaly Detection, Self-Supervised Learning, Deep-Learning for Tabular Data.
- Proposed three novel anomaly detection methods for tabular data: improved my project management capabilities.
- Supervised a research project of a 1st-year PhD Student: improved my management skills.
- Coded from scratch deep learning models in PyTorch and Python.
- Presented my research to multidisciplinary seminars: improved my **populariza**tion skills.

CentraleSupélec, Teacher in the Computer Science Department

Paris, Fr 2020 - 2024

- Course: Python (24h/year), Artificial Intelligence (20h/year).
- **Topics Covered**: OOP, Algorithmic, Data types, Machine Learning, Search Problems (e.g. Adversarial Search Problems, Local Search Problems), Markov Decision Process, Reinforcement Learning, Logic.

L'Oreal Research & Innovation, Deep Learning Scientist Intern

• Developed a **novel post-processing model to enforce temporal consistency in videos** which were processed frame by frame using non-transformation equivariant image-trained algorithms (Paper: here \(\mathcal{L}\)).

Paris, Fr 2019 (6 months)

Skills & Interests

Languages: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (B1), Russian (A2).

Coding: Python, LateX, SLURM, Gitlab/GitHub, UNIX.

ML Toolkit: PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, W&B, Docker.

Sport: Tennis, Running (STRAVA), Fly Fishing, Chess (4).

Volunteering: Mathematics teacher at Institut Villebon Georges Charpak (2019-2020).

Publications

Conference Proceedings

- [1] **Hugo Thimonier** et al. "Beyond Individual Input for Deep Anomaly Detection on Tabular Data". In: *Proceedings of the 41st International Conference on Machine Learning*. Ed. by Ruslan Salakhutdinov et al. Vol. 235. Proceedings of Machine Learning Research. PMLR, 21–27 Jul 2024, pp. 48097–48123. URL: https://proceedings.mlr.press/v235/thimonier24a.html.
- [2] **Hugo Thimonier** et al. "Comparative Evaluation of Anomaly Detection Methods for Fraud Detection in Online Credit Card Payments". In: *Proceedings of Ninth International Congress on Information and Communication Technology*. Ed. by Xin-She Yang et al. Singapore: Springer Nature Singapore, 2024, pp. 37–50. ISBN: 978-981-97-4581-4.
- [3] **Hugo Thimonier** et al. "Learning Long Term Style Preserving Blind Video Temporal Consistency". In: 2021 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME). 2021, pp. 1–6. DOI: 10.1109/ICME51207.2021.9428445
- [4] **Hugo Thimonier** et al. "Retrieval Augmented Deep Anomaly Detection for Tabular Data". In: *Proceedings of the 33rd ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM '24), Boise, ID, USA*. New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery, 2024. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3627673.3679559 .
- [6] **Hugo Thimonier** et al. "TracInAD: Measuring Influence for Anomaly Detection". In: 2022 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN). 2022, pp. 1–6. DOI: 10.1109/IJCNN55064.2022.9892058 ☑.

Preprints

[5] **Hugo Thimonier** et al. *T-JEPA: Augmentation-Free Self-Supervised Learning for Tabular Data*. 2024. arXiv: 2410.05016 [cs.LG] **C**. URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.05016.

References

Available on Request.